when creating documents within word
there may be occasions where you wish to
include some interactive element within
the document so just check boxes or
drop-down lists to do this you would
need to use the tools that are featured
on the Developer tab so if you look at
the top of your toolbar if the
development tab isn't available you
would first need to activate it to do
that if you go along to the word menu
and select Preferences and then ribbon
in tool bar and on the ribbon toolbar on
the right hand side you can see that the
main tabs are all ticked if the
developer tab isn't ticked you would
just need to tick that select Save and
then that will activate the Developer
tab so once you're on the Developer tab
you'll see a range of tools that can be
used to add various functionality to the
document the two that we're going to
focus on our check boxes aren't combo
box so for this first letter I'm just
going to add some simple check boxes
what I needed to do is place makers are
to the right of the first option and I'm
gonna use the tab key to line them up
just a little bit further away and then
I'm gonna click the check box icon which
will then insert a check box I will
repeat that for the next five options so
I move it down tab key add the check box
use the tab key check box
a tab key to line them up and finally
the last check box so now I have all the
check boxes inserted and that all lined
up and now I need to make them active
and to do that I need to click on the
protect form once you've clicked on the
protect form button you can then select
or deselect the check boxes as required
I can't edit any of the rest of the
document however anyone could unprotect
the form and then make changes to
protect the document fully you would
need to add a password and to do that
you would need to go to the Tools menu
from tools you would select protect
document that will then allow you to add
a password and the protection you're
looking for is to protect the document
four forms at the password select your
care and we'll ask you to repeat the
password select your care and that is
now set
so once the document has been protected
with a password by clicking on that you
would need to enter a password to
unprotect the document as well an ardent
checkboxes there may be occasions where
you wish to add a drop-down box so as
you can see I've slightly edited the
letter that I was working with and
reduced some of the options I'm now
gonna add some drop-down lists which
will indicate a specific number and then
the reader can then select that number
to see which experience that they're
interested in so again I'm on the
Developer tab and what I need to do is
I'm going to add your combo box so I'm
going to use the tab cages to space the
drop-down list away from the option
select a combo box and then click on
options now it's basically asking me
what I want to include in the drop-down
list so the first thing I'm going to add
some numbers so I click one and add that
two three four and finally five plus at
that so we now have all of the options I
want in the drop-down list and I'm just
going to edit the name so I just drop
down one remove the - from there and
click look here and that will have added
the drop-down list so I click on that
nothing happens
again you have to protect the form so
once it's protected I can then make
selections from the drop-down list
I'll just protect the form again now to
repeat that for the next two options I
would go again to the combo box do the
options and add the five numbers or
whatever else I wanted to add to the
drop-down box alternatively because I
know that the drop-down box is going to
be the same for both of the other
experiences I can just highlight that
use the command + C to copy it and go
down to the next option use a command in
V and again for that one
come on in V and then if I protect the
form I have now added the drop-down
lists to all three of the options as
with the forms if you wish to protect it
with a password you would need to go to
the Tools menu and then select protect
document and add a password